NANA ESI YAMOAH

Weija, Accra, Ghana | +233 (0) 546302363 | almighty.ney@gmail.com

SUMMARY

As a seasoned professional with over four years of experience in external audit, due diligence, accounting health checks, and similar services, I have demonstrated a strong focus on results throughout my career. My expertise lies in industries such as oil & gas, financial services, real estate, construction, NGOs, insurance, pensions, investment, etc. where I have consistently delivered innovative solutions and created value for my clients through comprehensive external audits.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- External audit
- Verbal and writing skills
- Proficient in MS suite
- Tax
- Time management

- QuickBooks
- Analytical skill
- Business planning
- Budgeting
- Problem solver

PROFESSIONAL ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Successfully secured 8 clients out of 15 proposals sent to potential customers.
- Managed payroll preparation for company staff and filed Personal Income Tax (PIT) for directors and employees for three consecutive years, maintaining a penalty-free record.
- Conducted IFRS 9 training for a financial institution's staff, ensuring compliance with accounting standards and Bank of Ghana's financial reporting guidelines.
- Provided training to junior staff, enabling them to effectively utilize QuickBooks for client bookkeeping.
- Successfully completed multiple audits, consistently meeting deadlines for all relevant regulatory bodies.

EXPERIENCE

UHY Voscon Chartered Accountants

Airport, Accra

Audit and Assurance & Tax – Semi Senior Associate to Senior Associate

July 2022- Date

- Provide management over a portfolio of clients and deliver high-quality audit and assurance service, including preparing and reviewing audit plans and work.
- Achieve team and individual audit budgets regarding timelines and resources.
- · Maintain the highest technical and professional standard requirements within the firm.
- Addressing situations before they become crises and developing solutions to avoid recurrence.
- Providing additional help and guidance to clients on a consultancy basis.
- Participate in the development of ways to meet client needs, and contribute to other assurance delivery
- like due diligence, and accounting health checks.
- Identifying ways to maximize the relationship with clients and deliver added value services.
- · Monitor and control auditing staff.
- Coach, train and develop auditing staff to upgrade their knowledge.

R-Alliance Consults

Dansoman, Accra

Audit and Assurance - Audit Associate

December 2020- July 2022

- · Assist in undertaking statutory audits on clients.
- Review payment vouchers and controls surrounding approval and payment of clients during audit assignments.
- Audit of payroll, cash and bank, PPE and other statutory payments during audit assignments.
- Assist in the preparation of audited financial statements.
- Assist in the preparation of management letters.
- Preparation of financial statements from Quick-Books.
- Support in preparation of Business Plan.
- Support in registration of Business.
- Assist in the submission of operational performance and reports of clients to their regulators.
- Assist in filing of taxes and annual returns at the Office of the Registrar of Companies (ORC).

Eros Group Company

Tuba, Kasoa

Accounts officer - Part time

September 2019- August 2020

- Maintain accurate financial records
- · Record day-to-day transactions
- Assist in preparing monthly, quarterly, and annual financial reports
- Manage employee expense reimbursements
- Help prepare and file tax returns such as Valued Added Tax (VAT), Pay As You Earn (PAYE), withholding tax, etc.

EDUCATION

Kwame Nkrumah University of Science & Technology

Kumasi

Accra

Idaho, USA

MBA International Business

2023-present

Bringham Young University - Online

BSc. Software Development

2023-present

Institute of Chartered Accountants Ghana

Professional Chartered Accountancy Certificate

2017 - 2019

ACHIEVEMENT

ICAG

Overall Best Audit and Assurance Student

May 2019

ICAG

Overall Best Female Student

May 2019

REFERENCE

Daniel Adewu (Mr.)

Partner

UHY Voscon Chartered Accountants

Tel: +233 (0) 201983678

• Daniel Adjei

Managing Partner,

R-Alliance Consults

Tel: +233 (0) 244646285